# Hai-Nguyen (Hann) Nguyen

## Ph.D., Mechanical Engineering | Roboticist

RIS, LAAS-CNRS Toulouse, France ☑ hann@laas.fr • http://hann.work

### Summary

Demonstrated working history at top research institutions in France, UK, Korea, and Vietnam. Strong research professional in robotics and autonomous systems with works published in top-tier journals/conferences, featured in media and demonstrated in public.

Research-minded programmer, proficient in C++/Python/ROS/PX4 with safetycertified and production-ready code on a variety of MCUs/sensors. Experienced in developing integrated hardware-software prototypes and industry-grade products in fast-paced Dev-Ops environments.

### Education

15.09.2012 - Ph.D. Mechanical & Aerospace Engineering, Seoul National University, Korea

26.02.2018 Thesis: Dynamics and Control of Quadrotor-based Aerial Manipulation Systems.

Committee: Prof. Frank C. Park (chair), Prof. Dongjun Lee (advisor), Prof. Kyujin Cho, Prof. Hyosung Ahn, and Prof. Kyungsoo Kim.

05.09.2003 - B.Eng. Mechatronics, M.Sc. Engineering Mechanics, Hanoi University of

04.07.2008, Science and Technology, Vietnam

15.10.2008 – Topics: Symbolic models of multibody systems (B.Eng.) and a formalism for multibody 13.01.2011 systems using null-space of Jacobian matrix (M.Sc.). Advisor: Prof. Van-Phong Dinh.

### Research Experience

05.07.2021 now

Contract Research Scientist, National Centre for Scientific Research (CNRS), France

Joined Robotics and InteractionS (RIS) group in LAAS-CNRS. Focus on the development of the foundations necessary to realize advanced aerial manipulation capability with a strong emphasis on robustness and dexterity. Initiated research projects and related collaborations along this line include:

#### Robustness aerial physical interaction

- O Developed an integrated framework for autonomous sensor placement with aerial robots [4], presenting a fully contained and accessible sensor placement approach capable of robust interaction with the environment.
- O Co-developed an aerial manipulator with shared compliance [5] with a study on combining mechanical compliance from the design with electronical compliance from the control.

#### Dexterous aerial manipulation

- O Co-developed a constrained Kalman filter for a cable-suspended aerial multirobot manipu-
- O Developed an algorithm for motion planning of a large-size aerial skeleton system with lock mechanisms.

#### 10.04.2018 - Research Associate, Imperial College London, UK

09.04.2020 Worked in Aerial Robotics Laboratory (ARL).

- O Developed an autonomous quadrotor system equipped with a winch-tethered magnet that is capable of perching on and sliding along a vertical surface for inspection at close proximity. The first realization of a tethered quadrotor that can hover and perch vertically near infrastructure elements, enabling a variety of surface manipulation and repair tasks. Live demos at EMPA, Switzerland (NEST), at Imperial College, UK (ORCA), at Blyth, UK (ORE Catapult) and to many visitors to ARL during 2019-2020.
- Developed planning and control algorithms for an aerial grappling robot to perch on a variety of surfaces including tree branches and pipelines (RoboSoft19).

### 15.09.2012 - Graduate Researcher, Seoul National University, Korea

26.02.2018 Worked in Interactive & Networked Robotics Laboratory (INRoL).

- O Developed a novel aerial platform (SmQ platform) to overcome the well-known under-actuation issues of multi-rotor drones in aerial operation/manipulation. Provided theoretical framework for its modeling and control, combining high-level Lyapunov control design (to achieve trajectory tracking) with low-level constrained optimization (to comply with physical constraints) (IROS15, TRO18, IEEE Spectrum, Interesting Engineering). Live demo to many experts in robotics visiting INRoL during 2015-2018.
- O Designed a control framework to enable a quadrotor to operate a tool attached on it. Fully characterized the internal dynamics of the spatial quadrotor tool operation, which arises due to the under-actuation of the quadrotor (IROS13, Automatica15).

### 01.09.2009 - Researcher, Vietnam Academy of Science and Technology, Vietnam

24.08.2012 Joined Department of Mechatronics, Institute of Mechanics in Sep. 2009 and became permanent researcher from Mar. 2010. Co-developed software/hardware for a 6-DOF manipulator prototype for welding.

01.12. 2007 – Intern, Graduate Researcher, Hanoi University of Science and Technology, 01.07. 2008. Vietnam

15.10. 2008 – Studied at Department of Applied Mechanics. Developed an algorithm for generating 01.09. 2009 symbolic models of tree-topology multibody systems (B.Eng. project) and a formalism for multibody systems using null-space of Jacobian matrix (M.Sc. project).

# Industry Experience

#### 23.03.2020 - Senior Robotic Engineer, Vimaan Robotics, Inc., CA, US (remote)

28.05.2021 Joined Autonomous Navigation Team in Santa Clara, CA (joined remotely due to the COVID-19 and visa delay). Focus on developing sensor fusion, control and planning algorithms for indoor autonomous robots, ranging from autopilot to mission generation.

- Developing trajectory generation and motion control for a hybrid ducted-fan/multi-rotor drones.
- Developed a range-aid feature for vision/inertia based state estimation, implemented on ECL/PX4 firmware and verified with existing flight data.
- Designed and implemented a route optimization algorithm for multiple aerial vehicles with limited flight time.

#### 01.09.2019 - Robotic Consultant, Imperial Consultants (ICON), UK

01.12.2019 Working with Uniper Energy on digitalization. Demonstrate and case study the use of autonomous flying robots for routine inspection and monitoring tasks at the power plants.

## Teaching Experience

May 2022 Guest Lecturer, University of Twente, Netherlands

(1) Control for UAVs (Spring 2022).

Mar. 2020 Teaching Assistant, Business School, Imperial College London, UK

(1) Imperial Leadership in a Technology Driven World Programme (Sberbank).

- Mar. 2019 Guest Lecturer, Imperial College London, UK
  - (1) Aircraft Systems Engineering and Unmanned Vehicle Technologies (Spring 2019, Spring 2020).
- Mar. 2019— Coach, UK STEM Ambassador, Shepherds Bush Library, UK
- May. 2019 (1) Code club (Python).
- Sep. 2013 **Teaching Assistant**, Seoul National University, Korea
  - Jul. 2017 (1) Control System I (Spring 2015, Spring 2016, Spring 2017).
    - (2) Control System II (Fall 2013, Fall 2014, Fall 2016).
    - (3) Robot Mechanics (Spring 2014, Spring 2016).

# Mentoring Experience

#### 2021-2022 RIS Group, LAAS-CNRS, France

Mentoring interns at LAAS:

- (1) Colomban Le-Falher, "Development of a flexible perching mechanism with integrated sensors for aerial robots", Master thesis, INSA, Strasbourg.
- (2) Leonardo Mouta Pereira Pinheiro, "Manipulating a cable-suspended object with multiple UAVs and environment contacts in 2D", Engineering thesis, Supaero, Toulouse.
- (3) Arthur Lotz, "Development of a perching robot", Engineering internship, Estaca.

#### 2018-2020 Aerial Robotics Lab, Imperial College London, UK

Mentoring phD student:

(1) Brett Stephens, "Interactive control and motion planning strategies for aerial manipulators in industrial environments", PhD student at Imperial College London.

Mentoring master students:

- (1) Bojia Mao, "Achieve Aerial Tensile Perching with Learning-Based Control Algorithm", Master thesis. Now Algorithm Engineer at Tencent.
- (2) Ronglong Ye, "Design and Manufacturing of a Passive Adapted Grapple for UAV Perching System", Master thesis. Now Sales Manager at Woco Group.
- (3) Alan Slatter, "Agile Tensile Perching with Micro Aerial Vehicles", Master thesis. Now Software Engineer at Amazon.
- (4) Brett Stephens, "Development of an Autonomously Perching Quadrotor Platform", Master thesis at ETH Zurich (internship at Imperial College). Now PhD candidate at Imperial College London.

# Technical Experience

- Coding C++/Python, Matlab/Maple, ROS/PX4, OpenCV/PCL, Git/Docker/Bash/SQL.
- Robots Multi-rotor drones, Manipulators, Underwater robot, Haptic devices, Motion capture systems, ARM-based MCUs.
- Sensors Distance (TFmini, Terabee), Depth camera (Realsense, Terabee), Mono IMU-Camera.
- Techniques Nonlinear control theory, Motion planning, Constrained Optimization, State estimation and Sensor fusion, VIO/SLAM.

### Media

- 2021 Imperial College London.
- 2020 Imperial College London, Telegraph.
- 2019 Reuters TV, BBC, Energy Voice, CNBC, Insider UK.
- 2018 Imperial College London, <u>EMPA</u>.

- 2017 Interesting Engineering, IEEE Spectrum.
- 2015 IEEE Spectrum.

### Research Funding

Jan. 2020 - Principal Investigator, ORCA Partnership Resource Fund, EPSRC (£164K), UK

Dec. 2020 Mixed-Reality Enhanced Telepresence for Remote Inspection and Monitoring with Multiple Aerial Robots. (later transferred to Co-PI before leaving Imperial)

### Honors and Awards

- 2018 Outstanding Contribution in Reviewing, Mechatronics Journal, Elsevier.
- 2017 Best Video Award, Korea Robotics Society Annual Conference.
- 2015 Travel Award, IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots & Systems.
- 2013 2015 Lecture & Research Scholarship, Seoul National University.
  - 2013 Global Scholarship, Seoul National University.
- 2012 2016 BK Scholarship, Brain Korea 21 & 21 Plus Program, Korea Government.
- 2010, 2011 Exceptional Researcher (Stakhanovite Appellation), Institute of Mechanics.
  - 2003 Merit-based Scholarship, Hanoi University of Science and Technology.
  - 2002 First Prize in Physics, Annual Excellent Student Competition, Haiphong City.
  - 2001 Third Prize in Biology, Annual Excellent Student Competition, Haiphong City.

### Academic Services

Edited and reviewed around 100 articles since 2014.

Assoc. Editor Ubiquitous Robots (2020, 2021),

IEEE Int'l Conference on Robotics & Automation (2023).

Section Chair Robotics: Science and Systems (2019).

Review IEEE Transactions on Robotics, IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters, Mechatronics, Nonlinear Dynamics, IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics.

IEEE Int'l Conference on Robotics & Automation (2015-now),

IEEE/RSJ Int'l Conference on Intelligent Robots & Systems (2014-now).

### Invited Talks

Dec. 2022 ICube - Université de Strasbourg, France

Empowering aerial robots with physical interaction capabilities.

Sep. 2022 Fulbright University, Vietnam

Empowering flying vehicles with physical interaction capabilities: from Control and Design perspectives.

Dec. 2019 Laboratory for Analysis and Architecture of Systems, CNRS, France Dynamics and Controls of Aerial Robots for Physical Interaction.

Nov. 2018 2030:A Martian Odyssey, Symposium for Extreme Habitats, UK Aerial Robotics for Infrastructures.

Mar. 2018 **Dept. Applied Mechanics**, *HUST*, Vietnam

Introduction of Aerial Manipulation Systems.

Jan. 2018 **Networked Robotic Systems Laboratory**, *NCKU*, Taiwan Aerial Robotic Systems for Physical Interaction.

### Patents

[1] D. J. Lee, **H. Nguyen** and H. Lee, "Aerial robot system based on multi-rotor for mechanical tasks," *Korea Patent No. 10-1614620-0000*, 2016.

### **Publications**

Detailed citation at Google Scholar Profile. Mentored-student authors are underlined.

- [1] **H. Nguyen**, B. Stephens, and M. Kovac. Aerial inspection at close proximity: a multi-modal mobility approach. 2023. (in preparation)
- [2] D. Sanalitro, **H. Nguyen**, J. Cortes, A. Franchi and S. Lacroix. State Estimation Improvement for a Cable-Suspended Aerial Multirobot Manipulator based on Constrained Kalman Filtering. (in preparation)
- [3] F. Hauf, B. B. Kocer, <u>A. Slatter</u>, **H. Nguyen**, O. K. F. Pang, R. Clark, E. Johns, and M. Kovac. Learning Tethered Perching for Aerial Robots. (submitted)
- [4] <u>B. Stephens</u>\*, **H. Nguyen**\*, S. Hamaza, and M. Kovac. An integrated framework for autonomous sensor placement with aerial robots. *IEEE/ASME Transactions on Mechatronics (TMech)*, 2022. (\* equal contribution)
- [5] B. Stephens, L. Orr, B. B. Kocer, H. Nguyen, M. Kovac. An Aerial Parallel Manipulator with Shared Compliance. *IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters* (RAL), 7(2):11902-11909, 2022. (with IROS option)
- [6] S. Hamaza, A. Farinha, H. Nguyen, and M. Kovac. Sensor Delivery in Forests with Aerial Robots: A New Paradigm to Environmental Monitoring. IROS Workshop on Perception, Planning and Mobility in Forestry Robotics (WPPMFR), 2020. (Best Paper Award)
- [7] D. Robb, M. Imtiaz Ahmad, C. Tiseo, S. Aracri, A. C. McConnell, V. Page, C. Dondrup, H. M. Taylor, P. Ardon, E. Pairet, L. J. Wilson, T. Semwal, H. Nguyen, H. Hastie, and K. Lohan. Robots in the danger zone: exploring public perception through engagement. ACM/IEEE Int'l Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (HRI), 2020.
- [8] **H. Nguyen**\*, R. Siddall\*, <u>B. Stephens</u>, A. Navarro-Rubio, M. Kovac. A passively adaptive microspine grapple for robust, controllable perching. *IEEE International Conference on Soft Robotics (RoboSoft)*, 2019. (\* equal contribution)
- [9] H. Nguyen, S. Park, J. Park, and D. J. Lee. A novel robotic platform for aerial manipulation using quadrotors as rotating thrust generators. *IEEE Transactions on Robotics (T-RO)*, 34(2):353-369, 2018.
- [10] **H. Nguyen**, C. Ha, and D. J. Lee. Mechanics, control and internal dynamics of quadrotor tool operation. *Automatica*, 61:289-301, 2015.
- [11] J. Bak, **H. Nguyen**, S. Park, D. J. Lee, T. Seo, S. Jin, and J. Kim. Positioning control of an underwater robot with tilting thrusters via decomposition of thrust vector.

- International Journal of Control, Automation and Systems (IJCAS), 15(5):2283-2291, 2017.
- [12] **H. Nguyen**, S. Park, and D. J. Lee. Aerial tool operation system using quadrotors as rotating thrust generators. In *Proc. IEEE/RSJ Int'l Conference on Intelligent Robots & Systems (IROS)*, pp. 1285-1291, 2015.
- [13] **H. Nguyen** and D. J. Lee. Hybrid force/motion control and internal dynamics of quadrotors for tool operation. In *Proc. IEEE/RSJ Int'l Conference on Intelligent Robots & Systems (IROS)*, pp. 3458-3464, 2013.
- [14] V-P. Dinh and **H. Nguyen**. A new approach using null space of Jacobian matrix in simulation of multibody dynamics. *Studies in Applied Electromagnetics and Mechanics*, 37:44-58, 2012.